<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ShardingSphere-JDBC on ShardingSphere</title>
    <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/1.5.0.M3/en/user-manual/shardingsphere-jdbc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ShardingSphere-JDBC on ShardingSphere</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/1.5.0.M3/en/user-manual/shardingsphere-jdbc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Properties Configuration</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/1.5.0.M3/en/user-manual/shardingsphere-jdbc/props/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/1.5.0.M3/en/user-manual/shardingsphere-jdbc/props/</guid>
      <description>Apache ShardingSphere provides the way of property configuration to configure system level configuration.
Configuration Item Explanation    Name Data Type Description Default Value     sql-show (?) boolean Whether show SQL or not in log. Print SQL details can help developers debug easier. The log details include: logic SQL, actual SQL and SQL parse result. Enable this property will log into log topic ShardingSphere-SQL, log level is INFO false   sql-simple (?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unsupported Items</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/1.5.0.M3/en/user-manual/shardingsphere-jdbc/unsupported/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/1.5.0.M3/en/user-manual/shardingsphere-jdbc/unsupported/</guid>
      <description>DataSource Interface  Do not support timeout related operations  Connection Interface  Do not support operations of stored procedure, function and cursor Do not support native SQL Do not support savepoint related operations Do not support Schema/Catalog operation Do not support self-defined type mapping  Statement and PreparedStatement Interface  Do not support statements that return multiple result sets (stored procedures, multiple pieces of non-SELECT data) Do not support the operation of international characters  ResultSet Interface  Do not support getting result set pointer position Do not support changing result pointer position through none-next method Do not support revising the content of result set Do not support acquiring international characters Do not support getting Array  JDBC 4.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>