<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Yaml Configuration on ShardingSphere</title>
    <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.5.1/en/user-manual/shardingsphere-proxy/yaml-config/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Yaml Configuration on ShardingSphere</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.5.1/en/user-manual/shardingsphere-proxy/yaml-config/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Authentication &amp; Authorization</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.5.1/en/user-manual/shardingsphere-proxy/yaml-config/authority/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.5.1/en/user-manual/shardingsphere-proxy/yaml-config/authority/</guid>
      <description>Background In ShardingSphere-Proxy, user authentication and authorization information is configured through authority.
Thanks to ShardingSphere&amp;rsquo;s pluggable architecture, Proxy provides two levels of privilege providers, namely:
 ALL_PERMITTED: each user has all privileges without special authorization. (Will be removed in a future version) DATABASE_PERMITTED: grants the user privileges on the specified logical databases, defined by user-database-mappings. (Recommended)  The administrator can choose which privilege provider to use as needed when configuring authority.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Properties</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.5.1/en/user-manual/shardingsphere-proxy/yaml-config/props/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.5.1/en/user-manual/shardingsphere-proxy/yaml-config/props/</guid>
      <description>Background Apache ShardingSphere provides a wealth of system configuration properties, which users can configure through global.yaml.
Parameters    Name Data Type Description Default Dynamic Update     system-log-level (?) String System log output level, supports DEBUG, INFO, WARN and ERROR, the default level is INFO. INFO True   sql-show (?) boolean Whether to print SQL in logs. Printing SQL can help developers quickly locate system problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rules</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.5.1/en/user-manual/shardingsphere-proxy/yaml-config/rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.5.1/en/user-manual/shardingsphere-proxy/yaml-config/rules/</guid>
      <description>Background This section explains how to configure the ShardingSphere-Proxy rules.
Parameters Explained Rules configuration for ShardingSphere-Proxy is the same as ShardingSphere-JDBC. For details, please refer to ShardingSphere-JDBC Rules Configuration.
Notice Unlike ShardingSphere-JDBC, the following rules need to be configured in ShardingSphere-Proxy&amp;rsquo;s global.yaml:
 SQL Parsing  sqlParser: sqlStatementCache: initialCapacity: 2000 maximumSize: 65535 parseTreeCache: initialCapacity: 128 maximumSize: 1024  Distributed Transaction  transaction: defaultType: XA providerType: Atomikos  SQL Translator  sqlTranslator: type: useOriginalSQLWhenTranslatingFailed:  SQL Federation  sqlFederation: sqlFederationEnabled: true allQueryUseSQLFederation: false executionPlanCache: initialCapacity: 2000 maximumSize: 65535 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Source</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.5.1/en/user-manual/shardingsphere-proxy/yaml-config/data-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.5.1/en/user-manual/shardingsphere-proxy/yaml-config/data-source/</guid>
      <description>Background ShardingSphere-Proxy supports common data source connection pools: HikariCP, C3P0, DBCP (C3P0, DBCP need download plugin from shardingsphere-plugins repository).
The connection pool can be specified through the parameter dataSourceClassName. When not specified, the default data source connection pool is HikariCP.
Parameters dataSources: # Data sources configuration, multiple &amp;lt;data-source-name&amp;gt; available &amp;lt;data_source_name&amp;gt;: # Data source name dataSourceClassName: # Data source connection pool full class name url: # The database URL connection username: # Database username password: # The database password # .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
