<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Encryption on ShardingSphere</title>
    <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-RC1/en/features/encrypt/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Encryption on ShardingSphere</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-RC1/en/features/encrypt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Core Concept</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-RC1/en/features/encrypt/concept/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-RC1/en/features/encrypt/concept/</guid>
      <description>TODO</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Principle</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-RC1/en/features/encrypt/principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-RC1/en/features/encrypt/principle/</guid>
      <description>Process Details Apache ShardingSphere can encrypt the plaintext by parsing and rewriting SQL according to the encryption rule, and store the plaintext (optional) and ciphertext data to the database at the same time. Queries data only extracts the ciphertext data from database and decrypts it, and finally returns the plaintext to user. Apache ShardingSphere transparently process of data encryption, so that users do not need to know to the implementation details of it, use encrypted data just like as regular data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Norms</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-RC1/en/features/encrypt/use-norms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-RC1/en/features/encrypt/use-norms/</guid>
      <description>Supported Items  The back-end databases are MySQL, Oracle, PostgreSQL, and SQLServer; The user needs to encrypt one or more columns in the database table (data encryption &amp;amp; decryption); Compatible with all commonly used SQL.  Unsupported Items  Users need to deal with the original inventory data and wash numbers in the database; Use encryption function + sub-database sub-table function, some special SQL is not supported, please refer to SQL specification; Encryption fields cannot support comparison operations, such as: greater than less than, ORDER BY, BETWEEN, LIKE, etc; Encryption fields cannot support calculation operations, such as AVG, SUM, and calculation expressions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>