<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Transaction on ShardingSphere</title>
    <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.1.2/en/reference/transaction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Transaction on ShardingSphere</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.1.2/en/reference/transaction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>XA Transaction</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.1.2/en/reference/transaction/2pc-xa-transaction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.1.2/en/reference/transaction/2pc-xa-transaction/</guid>
      <description>XAShardingSphereTransactionManager is XA transaction manager of Apache ShardingSphere. Its main responsibility is manage and adapt multiple data sources, and sent corresponding transactions to concrete XA transaction manager.
Transaction Begin When receiving set autoCommit=0 from client, XAShardingSphereTransactionManager will use XA transaction managers to start overall XA transactions, which is marked by XID.
Execute actual sharding SQL After XAShardingSphereTransactionManager register the corresponding XAResource to the current XA transaction, transaction manager will send XAResource.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seata BASE transaction</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.1.2/en/reference/transaction/base-transaction-seata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.1.2/en/reference/transaction/base-transaction-seata/</guid>
      <description>When integrating Seata AT transaction, we need to integrate TM, RM and TC component into ShardingSphere transaction manager. Seata have proxied DataSource interface in order to RPC with TC. Similarly, Apache ShardingSphere faced to DataSource interface to aggregate data sources too. After Seata DataSource encapsulation, it is easy to put Seata AT transaction into Apache ShardingSphere sharding ecosystem.
Init Seata Engine When an application containing ShardingSphereTransactionBaseSeataAT startup, the user-configured DataSource will be wrapped into seata DataSourceProxy through seata.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>