<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Contribution Conduct on ShardingSphere</title>
    <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/conduct/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Contribution Conduct on ShardingSphere</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/conduct/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Issue of Conduct</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/conduct/issue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/conduct/issue/</guid>
      <description>Issue Submit Conduct  Issue lists should be readable and retrievable, the author is obligated to summarize the title that is meaningful and convenient for retrieval, and to ensure the correctness and completeness of the content; Please confirm that there is no relevant existing Issue after sufficient search, and then submit a new Issue; The type of issue is divided into bug, new feature and problem. When you edit an issue, please select the correct template and fill in content according to the template; For problems caused by uncertain configuration, please submit the relevant reproducible code to GitHub, so that community contributors can locate and identify the problem more efficiently; Please reply to the Issue after it has been resolved to form a closed loop that will provide effective information for others who browse the Issue; Please pay attention to the submitted issues in time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code of Conduct</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/conduct/code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/conduct/code/</guid>
      <description>The following code of conduct is based on full compliance with ASF CODE OF CONDUCT.
Development Guidelines  Write codes with heart. Pursue clean, simplified and extremely elegant codes. Agree with concepts in &amp;lt;Refactoring: Improving the Design of Existing Code&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;Clean Code: A Handbook of Agile Software Craftsmanship&amp;gt;. Be familiar with codes already had, to keep consistent with the style and use. Highly reusable, no duplicated codes or configurations. Delete codes out of use in time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Document of Conduct</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/conduct/document/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/conduct/document/</guid>
      <description>The title of topic should in title = &amp;quot;xxx&amp;quot; only, content should not include main title(#); Please leave a blank line at the end of topic; To avoid segment too long, please start a new line after full stop; Please keep a blank line between title and content; For reading friendly, please arrange for each column in table beside last one; Please keep space between | and - in head of table; Please use 1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>