<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Core Concept on ShardingSphere</title>
    <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-RC1/en/features/sharding/concept/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Core Concept on ShardingSphere</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-RC1/en/features/sharding/concept/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Table</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-RC1/en/features/sharding/concept/table/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-RC1/en/features/sharding/concept/table/</guid>
      <description>Logic Table It refers collectively to horizontal sharding databases (tables) with the same logic and data structure. For instance, the order data is divided into 10 tables according to the last number of the primary key, and they are from t_order_0 to t_order_9, whose logic name is t_order.
Actual Table The physical table that really exists in the sharding database, i.e., t_order_0 to t_order_9 in the instance above.
Data Node As the smallest unit of sharding, it consists of data source name and table name, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sharding</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-RC1/en/features/sharding/concept/sharding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-RC1/en/features/sharding/concept/sharding/</guid>
      <description>Sharding Key The database field used in sharding refers to the key field in horizontal sharding of the database (table). For example, in last number modulo of order ID sharding, order ID is taken as the sharding key. The full route executed when there is no sharding field in SQL has a poor performance. Besides single sharding column, Apache ShardingSphere also supports multiple sharding columns.
Sharding Algorithm Data sharding can be achieved by sharding algorithms through =, &amp;gt;=, &amp;lt;=, &amp;gt;, &amp;lt;, BETWEEN and IN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-RC1/en/features/sharding/concept/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-RC1/en/features/sharding/concept/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Sharding Rule The main entrance for Sharding rules includes the configurations of data source, tables, binding tables and readwrite-splitting.
Data Sources Configuration Real data sources list.
Tables Configuration Configurations of logic table names, data node and table sharding rules.
Data Node Configuration It is used in the configurations of the mapping relationship between logic tables and actual tables and can be divided into two kinds: uniform distribution and user-defined distribution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inline Expression</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-RC1/en/features/sharding/concept/inline-expression/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-RC1/en/features/sharding/concept/inline-expression/</guid>
      <description>Motivation Configuration simplicity and unity are two main problems that inline expression intends to solve.
In complex sharding rules, with more data nodes, a large number of configuration repetitions make configurations difficult to maintain. Inline expressions can simplify data node configuration work.
Java codes are not helpful in the unified management of common configurations. Writing sharding algorithms with inline expressions, users can stored rules together, making them easier to be browsed and stored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed Primary Key</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-RC1/en/features/sharding/concept/key-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-RC1/en/features/sharding/concept/key-generator/</guid>
      <description>Motivation In the development of traditional database software, the automatic sequence generation technology is a basic requirement. All kinds of databases have provided corresponding support for this requirement, such as MySQL auto-increment key, Oracle auto-increment sequence and so on. It is a tricky problem that there is only one sequence generated by different data nodes after sharding. Auto-increment keys in different physical tables in the same logic table can not perceive each other and thereby generate repeated sequences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hint Sharding Route</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-RC1/en/features/sharding/concept/hint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-RC1/en/features/sharding/concept/hint/</guid>
      <description>Motivation Apache ShardingSphere can be compatible with SQL in way of parsing SQL statements and extracting columns and values to shard. If SQL does not have sharding conditions, it is impossible to shard without full route.
In some applications, sharding conditions are not in SQL but in external business logic. So it requires to designate sharding result externally, which is referred to as Hint in ShardingSphere.
Mechanism Apache ShardingSphere uses ThreadLocal to manage sharding key values.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>