<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Readwrite-splitting on ShardingSphere</title>
    <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/2.0.0.M1/en/features/readwrite-splitting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Readwrite-splitting on ShardingSphere</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/2.0.0.M1/en/features/readwrite-splitting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Core Concept</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/2.0.0.M1/en/features/readwrite-splitting/concept/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/2.0.0.M1/en/features/readwrite-splitting/concept/</guid>
      <description>Primary Database It refers to the database used in data insertion, update and deletion. It only supports single primary database for now.
Replica Database It refers to the database used in data query. It supports multiple replica databases.
Primary Replica Replication It refers to the operation to asynchronously replicate data from the primary database to the replica database. Because of the asynchrony of primary-replica synchronization, there may be short-time data inconsistency between them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Norms</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/2.0.0.M1/en/features/readwrite-splitting/use-norms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/2.0.0.M1/en/features/readwrite-splitting/use-norms/</guid>
      <description>Supported  Provide the readwrite-splitting configuration of one primary database with multiple replica databases, which can be used alone or with sharding table and database; Primary nodes need to be used for both reading and writing in the transaction; Forcible primary database route based on SQL Hint;  Unsupported  Data replication between the primary and the replica databases; Data inconsistency caused by replication delay between databases; Double or multiple primary databases to provide write operation; The data for transaction across primary and replica nodes are inconsistent; In the readwrite-splitting model, primary nodes need to be used for both reading and writing in the transaction.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>