<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ShardingSphere</title>
    <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content on ShardingSphere</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributor Guide</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/contribute/contributor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/contribute/contributor/</guid>
      <description>You can report a bug, submit a new function enhancement suggestion, or submit a pull request directly.
Submit an Issue  Before submitting an issue, please go through a comprehensive search to make sure the problem cannot be solved just by searching. Check the Issue List to make sure the problem is not repeated. Create a new issue and choose the type of issue. Define the issue with a clear and descriptive title.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Issue of Conduct</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/conduct/issue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/conduct/issue/</guid>
      <description>Issue Submit Conduct  Issue lists should be readable and retrievable, the author is obligated to summarize the title that is meaningful and convenient for retrieval, and to ensure the correctness and completeness of the content; Please confirm that there is no relevant existing Issue after sufficient search, and then submit a new Issue; The type of issue is divided into bug, new feature and problem. When you edit an issue, please select the correct template and fill in content according to the template; For problems caused by uncertain configuration, please submit the relevant reproducible code to GitHub, so that community contributors can locate and identify the problem more efficiently; Please reply to the Issue after it has been resolved to form a closed loop that will provide effective information for others who browse the Issue; Please pay attention to the submitted issues in time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responsibilities &amp; Routine</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/committer/responsibilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/committer/responsibilities/</guid>
      <description>Responsibilities  Develop new features; Refactor codes; Review pull requests reliably and in time; Consider and accept feature requests; Answer questions; Update documentation and example; Improve processes and tools; Check whether CI Scheduled Workflow works or not periodically; Guide new contributors join community.  Routine  Check the list of pull requests and issues to be processed in the community on a daily basis.   Including label issue, reply issue, close issue; Assign issue to the appropriate committer, namely assignee;  After a committer is assigned with an issue, the following work is required:   Estimate whether it is a long-term issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ShardingSphere Release Guide</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/release/shardingsphere/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/release/shardingsphere/</guid>
      <description>Prepare before release 1. Confirm release notes The release note should be provided in English / Chinese, confirm whether English and Chinese description are clear, and shall be classified according to the following labels:
 New Feature API Change Enhancement Bug Fix  2. Confirm issue list Open GitHub issues, filter the issue whose milestone is ${RELEASE.VERSION} and status is open:
 Close the completed issue; For outstanding issues, communicate with the developer in charge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subscribe Guide</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/subscribe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/subscribe/</guid>
      <description>When using or contributing to ShardingSphere, if you encounter any problem, or you have any suggestions or new ideas, you can use the Apache mailing-list to participate in the community building, or join the ShardingSphere Slack channel to connect with other community members.
To join the mailing list:
  Send an e-mail to subscribe. Use your mailbox to send an e-mail to dev-subscribe@shardingsphere.apache.org with any subject or content.
  Receive and reply the confirmation e-mail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code of Conduct</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/conduct/code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/conduct/code/</guid>
      <description>The following code of conduct is based on full compliance with ASF CODE OF CONDUCT.
Development Guidelines  Write codes with heart. Pursue clean, simplified and extremely elegant codes. Agree with concepts in &amp;lt;Refactoring: Improving the Design of Existing Code&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;Clean Code: A Handbook of Agile Software Craftsmanship&amp;gt;. Be familiar with codes already had, to keep consistent with the style and use. Highly reusable, no duplicated codes or configurations. Delete codes out of use in time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Set Up Your DEV Environment</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/contribute/dev-env/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/contribute/dev-env/</guid>
      <description>Git Installation Use the latest version.
You could download Git from Git Downloads.
If you&amp;rsquo;re running macOS or Linux, you could install Git from software repository.
Git Settings If you&amp;rsquo;re running Windows, following settings should be done before cloning ShardingSphere code.
Execute following command in PowerShell or cmd to prevent from filename too long error on cloning ShardingSphere code:
git config --global core.longpaths true JDK Installation Use JDK8+.
You could download JDK from OpenJDK Downloads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New committer voting process</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/committer/vote/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/committer/vote/</guid>
      <description>The Apache ShardingSphere community follows the Apache Community’s process on accepting a new committer. After a contributor participates community actively, PMC and Committers will make a decision to invite the contributor to join Committers and PMC.
1. Start the discussion and vote in @private. Only current PMC member could nominate.
Example:
To：private@shardingsphere.apache.org Title: [VOTE] New committer:(nominee) Content: Hi, everyone This is ^a formal vote^ about inviting (nominee)as our new committer. He/She really made an effort to improve ShardingSphere Parser and fix many issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ShardingSphere on Cloud Release Guide</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/release/shardingsphere-on-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/release/shardingsphere-on-cloud/</guid>
      <description>Prepare before release 1. Confirm release notes The release note should be provided in English / Chinese, confirm whether English and Chinese description are clear, and shall be classified according to the following labels:
 New Feature API Change Enhancement Bug Fix  2. Confirm issue list Open Github Issues, filter the issue whose milestone is ${RELEASE.VERSION} and status is open:
 Close the completed issue; For outstanding issues, communicate with the developer in charge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Document of Conduct</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/conduct/document/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/conduct/document/</guid>
      <description>The title of topic should in title = &amp;quot;xxx&amp;quot; only, content should not include main title(#); Please leave a blank line at the end of topic; To avoid segment too long, please start a new line after full stop; Please keep a blank line between title and content; For reading friendly, please arrange for each column in table beside last one; Please keep space between | and - in head of table; Please use 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Documents Contribute Guide</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/contribute/document/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/contribute/document/</guid>
      <description>If you want to help contribute shardingsphere documents or websites, we are happy to help you! Anyone can contribute, whether you&amp;rsquo;re new to a project or have been using shardingsphere for a long time, whether you&amp;rsquo;re a self identified developer, end-user, or someone who can&amp;rsquo;t stand typos,can contribute to documents or websites. In the contributor guide, we have mentioned how to submit Issues and pull request. here we will introduce how to submit pull request to document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ElasticJob Release Guide</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/release/elasticjob/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/release/elasticjob/</guid>
      <description>Preparation GPG Setup Please refer to Release Guide.
Setting settings.xml Add the following template to ~/.m2/settings.xml, all the passwords need to be filled in after encryption. For encryption settings, please see here.
&amp;lt;settings&amp;gt; &amp;lt;servers&amp;gt; &amp;lt;server&amp;gt; &amp;lt;id&amp;gt;apache.snapshots.https&amp;lt;/id&amp;gt; &amp;lt;username&amp;gt; &amp;lt;!-- APACHE LDAP username --&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/username&amp;gt; &amp;lt;password&amp;gt; &amp;lt;!-- APACHE LDAP encrypted password --&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/password&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/server&amp;gt; &amp;lt;server&amp;gt; &amp;lt;id&amp;gt;apache.releases.https&amp;lt;/id&amp;gt; &amp;lt;username&amp;gt; &amp;lt;!-- APACHE LDAP username --&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/username&amp;gt; &amp;lt;password&amp;gt; &amp;lt;!-- APACHE LDAP encrypted password --&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/password&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/server&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/servers&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/settings&amp;gt; Publishing Apache Snapshot Deploying to Apache Snapshot Repository 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sign ICLA Guide</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/committer/icla/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/committer/icla/</guid>
      <description>Sign Apache ICLA guide Apache CLA short for Apache Contributor License Agreement, the purpose of this agreement is to clearly define the terms under which intellectual property has been contributed to the ASF and thereby allow us to defend the project should there be a legal dispute regarding the software at some future time. A signed ICLA is required to be on file before an individual is given commit rights to any ASF project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2FA</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/committer/2fa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/committer/2fa/</guid>
      <description>Two-factor authentication(2FA) Two factor authentication (2FA) refers to the authentication method that combines both passport, and an object (credit card, SMS phone, token or biomarkers as fingerprint) to identify a user. To ensure the security of the committer’s account, we need you to enable 2FA to sign in and contribute codes on GitHub.
More details, please refer to 2FA.
 To be noticed: If you do not enable 2FA, you will be removed from the project and unable to access our repositories and the fork from our private repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ElasticJob UI Release Guide</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/release/elasticjob-ui/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/release/elasticjob-ui/</guid>
      <description>GPG Settings Please refer to Release Guide.
Apache Maven Central Repository Release 1. Set settings.xml
Add the following template to ~/.m2/settings.xml, all the passwords need to be filled in after encryption. For encryption settings, please see here.
&amp;lt;settings&amp;gt; &amp;lt;servers&amp;gt; &amp;lt;server&amp;gt; &amp;lt;id&amp;gt;apache.snapshots.https&amp;lt;/id&amp;gt; &amp;lt;username&amp;gt; &amp;lt;!-- APACHE LDAP username --&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/username&amp;gt; &amp;lt;password&amp;gt; &amp;lt;!-- APACHE LDAP encrypted password --&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/password&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/server&amp;gt; &amp;lt;server&amp;gt; &amp;lt;id&amp;gt;apache.releases.https&amp;lt;/id&amp;gt; &amp;lt;username&amp;gt; &amp;lt;!-- APACHE LDAP username --&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/username&amp;gt; &amp;lt;password&amp;gt; &amp;lt;!-- APACHE LDAP encrypted password --&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/password&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/server&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/servers&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/settings&amp;gt; 2.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>