<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Operation on ElasticJob</title>
    <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/elasticjob/current/en/user-manual/elasticjob-lite/operation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Operation on ElasticJob</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shardingsphere.apache.org/elasticjob/current/en/user-manual/elasticjob-lite/operation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy Guide</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/elasticjob/current/en/user-manual/elasticjob-lite/operation/deploy-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/elasticjob/current/en/user-manual/elasticjob-lite/operation/deploy-guide/</guid>
      <description>Application deployment  Start the ZooKeeper of the ElasticJob-Lite designated registry. Run the jar file containing ElasticJob-Lite and business code. It is not limited to the startup mode of jar or war. When the job server is configured with multiple network cards, the network card address can be specified by setting the system variable elasticjob.preferred.network.interface or specify network addresses by setting the system variable elasticjob.preferred.network.ip. ElasticJob obtains the first non-loopback available IPV4 address in the network card list by default.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dump Job Information</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/elasticjob/current/en/user-manual/elasticjob-lite/operation/dump/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/elasticjob/current/en/user-manual/elasticjob-lite/operation/dump/</guid>
      <description>Using ElasticJob may meet some distributed problem which is not easy to observe.
Because of developer cannot debug in production environment, ElasticJob provide dump command to export job runtime information for debugging.
For security reason, the information dumped had already mask sensitive information, it instead of real IP address to ip1, ip2 &amp;hellip;
Open Listener Port Using Java API please refer to Java API usage for more details. Using Spring please refer to Spring usage for more details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Execution Monitor</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/elasticjob/current/en/user-manual/elasticjob-lite/operation/execution-monitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/elasticjob/current/en/user-manual/elasticjob-lite/operation/execution-monitor/</guid>
      <description>By monitoring several key nodes in the zookeeper registry of ElasticJob-Lite, the job running status monitoring function can be completed.
Monitoring job server alive Listen for the existence of node job_name\instances\job_instance_id. This node is a temporary node. If the job server is offline, the node will be deleted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Console</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/elasticjob/current/en/user-manual/elasticjob-lite/operation/web-console/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/elasticjob/current/en/user-manual/elasticjob-lite/operation/web-console/</guid>
      <description>Unzip elasticjob-lite-console-${version}.tar.gz and execute bin\start.sh. Open the browser and visit http://localhost:8899/ to access the console. 8899 is the default port number. You can customize the port number by entering -p through the startup script.
Log in The console provides two types of accounts: administrator and guest. The administrator has all operation rights, and the visitors only have the viewing rights. The default administrator user name and password are root/root，and the guest user name and password are guest/guest，You can modify the administrator and guest user names and passwords through conf\application.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>