<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Resource Definition on ShardingSphere</title>
    <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/3.0.0/en/reference/distsql/syntax/rdl/resource-definition/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Resource Definition on ShardingSphere</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/3.0.0/en/reference/distsql/syntax/rdl/resource-definition/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ADD RESOURCE</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/3.0.0/en/reference/distsql/syntax/rdl/resource-definition/add-resource/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/3.0.0/en/reference/distsql/syntax/rdl/resource-definition/add-resource/</guid>
      <description>Description The ADD RESOURCE syntax is used to add resources for the currently selected schema.
Syntax AddResource ::= &amp;#39;ADD&amp;#39; &amp;#39;RESOURCE&amp;#39; dataSource (&amp;#39;,&amp;#39; dataSource)* dataSource ::= dataSourceName &amp;#39;(&amp;#39; ( &amp;#39;HOST&amp;#39; &amp;#39;=&amp;#39; hostName &amp;#39;,&amp;#39; &amp;#39;PORT&amp;#39; &amp;#39;=&amp;#39; port &amp;#39;,&amp;#39; &amp;#39;DB&amp;#39; &amp;#39;=&amp;#39; dbName | &amp;#39;URL&amp;#39; &amp;#39;=&amp;#39; url ) &amp;#39;,&amp;#39; &amp;#39;USER&amp;#39; &amp;#39;=&amp;#39; user (&amp;#39;,&amp;#39; &amp;#39;PASSWORD&amp;#39; &amp;#39;=&amp;#39; password )? (&amp;#39;,&amp;#39; &amp;#39;PROPERTIES&amp;#39; &amp;#39;(&amp;#39; ( key &amp;#39;=&amp;#39; value ) ( &amp;#39;,&amp;#39; key &amp;#39;=&amp;#39; value )* &amp;#39;)&amp;#39; )?&amp;#39;)&amp;#39; dataSourceName ::= identifier hostname ::= identifier | ip dbName ::= identifier port ::= int password ::= identifier | int | string user ::= identifier url ::= identifier | string Supplement  Before adding resources, please confirm that a schema has been created in Proxy, and execute the use command to successfully select a schema Confirm that the added resource can be connected normally, otherwise it will not be added successfully dataSourceName is case-sensitive dataSourceName needs to be unique within the current schema dataSourceName name only allows letters, numbers and _, and must start with a letter poolProperty is used to customize connection pool parameters, key must be the same as the connection pool parameter name, value supports int and String types When password contains special characters, it is recommended to use the string form; for example, the string form of password@123 is &amp;quot;password@123&amp;quot;  Example  Add resource using standard mode  ADD RESOURCE ds_0 ( HOST=127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DROP RESOURCE</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/3.0.0/en/reference/distsql/syntax/rdl/resource-definition/drop-resource/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/3.0.0/en/reference/distsql/syntax/rdl/resource-definition/drop-resource/</guid>
      <description>Description The DROP RESOURCE syntax is used to drop resources from the current schema
Syntax DropResource ::= &amp;#39;DROP&amp;#39; &amp;#39;RESOURCE&amp;#39; ( &amp;#39;IF&amp;#39; &amp;#39;EXISTS&amp;#39; )? dataSourceName ( &amp;#39;,&amp;#39; dataSourceName )* ( &amp;#39;IGNORE&amp;#39; &amp;#39;SINGLE&amp;#39; &amp;#39;TABLES&amp;#39; )? Supplement  DROP RESOURCE will only drop resources in Proxy, the real data source corresponding to the resource will not be dropped Unable to drop resources already used by rules. Resources are still in used. will be prompted when removing resources used by rules The resource need to be removed only contains SINGLE TABLE RULE, and when the user confirms that this restriction can be ignored, the IGNORE SINGLE TABLES keyword can be added to remove the resource  Example  Drop a resource  DROP RESOURCE ds_0;  Drop multiple resources  DROP RESOURCE ds_1, ds_2;  Ignore single table rule remove resource  DROP RESOURCE ds_1 IGNORE SINGLE TABLES;  Drop the resource if it exists  DROP RESOURCE IF EXISTS ds_2; Reserved word DROP, RESOURCE, IF, EXISTS, IGNORE, SINGLE, TABLES  Related links  Reserved word  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>