<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shadow DB on ShardingSphere</title>
    <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-RC1/en/features/shadow/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Shadow DB on ShardingSphere</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-RC1/en/features/shadow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Core Concept</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-RC1/en/features/shadow/concept/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-RC1/en/features/shadow/concept/</guid>
      <description>Shadow DB Switch Shadow library switch.
A stress test is a demand for a specific period of time, and it can be turned on when needed.
Production DB The database used for production data.
Shadow DB The database used for the test data.
Shadow Table Perform pressure test data related tables.
It has the same table structure as the corresponding table in the production database.
Shadow Algorithm Provides 2 types of shadow algorithms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Principle</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-RC1/en/features/shadow/principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-RC1/en/features/shadow/principle/</guid>
      <description>Overall Architecture Apache ShardingSphere makes shadow judgments on incoming SQL by parsing SQL, according to the shadow rules set by the user in the configuration file, route to production DB or shadow DB.
Shadow Rule Shadow rules include shadow data source mapping, shadow tables, and shadow algorithms.
enable：Shadow DB switch, The default value is false. Optional value true/false.
data-sources：Production data source name and shadow data source name mappings.
tables：For tables related to stress testing, shadow tables must be included in the shadow library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Norms</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-RC1/en/features/shadow/use-norms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-RC1/en/features/shadow/use-norms/</guid>
      <description>Shadow database Supported Items  The database is MySQL, Oracle, PostgreSQL, SQLServer;  Unsupported Items  NoSQL database;  Shadow algorithm Supported Items  The note shadow algorithm supports MDL and DDL statements; The column shadow algorithm basically supports commonly used MDL statements;  Unsupported Items  Column shadow algorithm does not support DDL statements； The column shadow algorithm does not support range value matching operations, for example: subQuery, BETWEEN, GROUP BY &amp;hellip; HAVING&amp;hellip;; Use shadow library function + sub-library sub-table function, some special SQL is not supported, please refer toSQL Usage Specification  Column shadow algorithm DML statement support list  INSERT statement  Judge the inserted column and inserted value of INSERT operation</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>