<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Core Concept on ShardingSphere</title>
    <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-RC1/en/features/transaction/concept/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Core Concept on ShardingSphere</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-RC1/en/features/transaction/concept/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>XA Transaction</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-RC1/en/features/transaction/concept/2pc-xa-transaction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-RC1/en/features/transaction/concept/2pc-xa-transaction/</guid>
      <description>2PC transaction submit uses the DTP Model defined by X/OPEN, in which created AP (Application Program), TM (Transaction Manager) and RM (Resource Manager) can guarantee a high transaction consistency. TM and RM use XA protocol for bidirectional streaming. Compared with traditional local transactions, XA transactions have a prepared phase, where the database cannot only passively receive commands, but also notify the submitter whether the transaction can be accepted. TM can collect all the prepared results of branch transactions before submitting all of them together, which has guaranteed the distributed consistency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seata BASE transaction</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-RC1/en/features/transaction/concept/base-transaction-seata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-RC1/en/features/transaction/concept/base-transaction-seata/</guid>
      <description>Seata is a distributed transaction framework developed by Alibaba Group and Ant Finance. The goal of AT transaction is to provide incremental transaction ACID semantics under the micro-service architecture, so that developers can use distributed transactions as they use local transactions. The core idea of AT transaction is the same as Apache ShardingSphere.
Seata AT transaction model includes TM (Transaction Manager), RM (Resource Manager) and TC (Transaction Coordinator). TC is an independent service that needs to be deployed separately.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>