<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CDC on ShardingSphere</title>
    <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.5.1/en/user-manual/shardingsphere-proxy/cdc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CDC on ShardingSphere</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.5.1/en/user-manual/shardingsphere-proxy/cdc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Build</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.5.1/en/user-manual/shardingsphere-proxy/cdc/build/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.5.1/en/user-manual/shardingsphere-proxy/cdc/build/</guid>
      <description>Background Information ShardingSphere CDC is divided into two parts, one is the CDC Server, and the other is the CDC Client. The CDC Server and ShardingSphere-Proxy are currently deployed together.
Users can introduce the CDC Client into their own projects to implement data consumption logic.
Constraints  Pure JAVA development, JDK recommended 1.8 or above. CDC Server requires ShardingSphere-Proxy to use cluster mode, currently supports ZooKeeper as the registry center. CDC only synchronizes data, does not synchronize table structure, and currently does not support DDL statement synchronization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manual</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.5.1/en/user-manual/shardingsphere-proxy/cdc/usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.5.1/en/user-manual/shardingsphere-proxy/cdc/usage/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to CDC Function CDC only synchronizes data, it does not synchronize table structures, and currently does not support the synchronization of DDL statements.
Introduction to CDC Protocol The CDC protocol uses Protobuf, and the corresponding Protobuf types are mapped based on the types in Java.
Here, taking openGauss as an example, the mapping relationship between the data types of the CDC protocol and the database types is as follows.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
