<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Committer Guide on ShardingSphere</title>
    <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/committer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Committer Guide on ShardingSphere</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/committer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Responsibilities &amp; Routine</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/committer/responsibilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/committer/responsibilities/</guid>
      <description>Responsibilities  Develop new features; Refactor codes; Review pull requests reliably and in time; Consider and accept feature requests; Answer questions; Update documentation and example; Improve processes and tools; Check whether CI Scheduled Workflow works or not periodically; Guide new contributors join community.  Routine  Check the list of pull requests and issues to be processed in the community on a daily basis.   Including label issue, reply issue, close issue; Assign issue to the appropriate committer, namely assignee;  After a committer is assigned with an issue, the following work is required:   Estimate whether it is a long-term issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New committer voting process</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/committer/vote/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/committer/vote/</guid>
      <description>The Apache ShardingSphere community follows the Apache Community’s process on accepting a new committer. After a contributor participates community actively, PMC and Committers will make a decision to invite the contributor to join Committers and PMC.
1. Start the discussion and vote in @private. Only current PMC member could nominate.
Example:
To：private@shardingsphere.apache.org Title: [VOTE] New committer:(nominee) Content: Hi, everyone This is ^a formal vote^ about inviting (nominee)as our new committer. He/She really made an effort to improve ShardingSphere Parser and fix many issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sign ICLA Guide</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/committer/icla/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/committer/icla/</guid>
      <description>Sign Apache ICLA guide Apache CLA short for Apache Contributor License Agreement, the purpose of this agreement is to clearly define the terms under which intellectual property has been contributed to the ASF and thereby allow us to defend the project should there be a legal dispute regarding the software at some future time. A signed ICLA is required to be on file before an individual is given commit rights to any ASF project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2FA</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/committer/2fa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/committer/2fa/</guid>
      <description>Two-factor authentication(2FA) Two factor authentication (2FA) refers to the authentication method that combines both passport, and an object (credit card, SMS phone, token or biomarkers as fingerprint) to identify a user. To ensure the security of the committer’s account, we need you to enable 2FA to sign in and contribute codes on GitHub.
More details, please refer to 2FA.
 To be noticed: If you do not enable 2FA, you will be removed from the project and unable to access our repositories and the fork from our private repository.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>