<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Operation on ElasticJob</title>
    <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/elasticjob/current/en/user-manual/elasticjob-cloud/operation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Operation on ElasticJob</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shardingsphere.apache.org/elasticjob/current/en/user-manual/elasticjob-cloud/operation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy Guide</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/elasticjob/current/en/user-manual/elasticjob-cloud/operation/deploy-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/elasticjob/current/en/user-manual/elasticjob-cloud/operation/deploy-guide/</guid>
      <description>Scheduler deployment steps  Start ElasticJob-Cloud-Scheduler and Mesos, and specify ZooKeeper as the registry. Start Mesos Master and Mesos Agent. Unzip elasticjob-cloud-scheduler-${version}.tar.gz. Run bin\start.sh to start ElasticJob-Cloud-Scheduler.  Job deployment steps  Ensure that ZooKeeper, Mesos Master/Agent and ElasticJob-Cloud-Scheduler have been started correctly. Place the tar.gz file of the packaging job in a network accessible location, such as ftp or http. The main method in the packaged tar.gz file needs to call the JobBootstrap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High Available</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/elasticjob/current/en/user-manual/elasticjob-cloud/operation/high-availability/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/elasticjob/current/en/user-manual/elasticjob-cloud/operation/high-availability/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The high availability of the scheduler is achieved by running several ElasticJob-Cloud-Scheduler instances pointing to the same ZooKeeper cluster. ZooKeeper is used to perform leader election when the current primary ElasticJob-Cloud-Scheduler instance fails. At least two scheduler instances are used to form a cluster. Only one scheduler instance in the cluster provides services, and the other instances are in the standby state. When the instance fails, the cluster will elect one of the remaining instances to continue providing services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Console</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/elasticjob/current/en/user-manual/elasticjob-cloud/operation/web-console/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/elasticjob/current/en/user-manual/elasticjob-cloud/operation/web-console/</guid>
      <description>The operation and maintenance platform is embedded in the jar package of elasticjob-cloud-scheduler, and there is no need to start an additional WEB server. The startup port can be adjusted by modifying the http_port parameter in the configuration file. The default port is 8899 and the access address is http://{your_scheduler_ip}:8899.
Log in Two types of accounts are provided, administrator and guest. The administrator has all operation permissions, and the visitor only has viewing permissions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>