<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Use Norms on ShardingSphere</title>
    <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-beta/en/features/transaction/use-norms/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Use Norms on ShardingSphere</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-beta/en/features/transaction/use-norms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Local Transaction</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-beta/en/features/transaction/use-norms/local-transaction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-beta/en/features/transaction/use-norms/local-transaction/</guid>
      <description>Supported Items  Fully support none-cross-database transactions, for example, sharding table or sharding database with its route result in one database; Fully support cross-database transactions caused by logic exceptions, for example, the update of two databases in one transaction, after which, databases will throw null cursor and the content in both databases can be rolled back.  Unsupported Items  Do not support the cross-database transactions caused by network or hardware exceptions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XA transaction</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-beta/en/features/transaction/use-norms/2pc-xa-transaction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-beta/en/features/transaction/use-norms/2pc-xa-transaction/</guid>
      <description>Supported Items  Support cross-database transactions after sharding; Operation atomicity and high data consistency in 2PC transactions; When service is down and restarted, commit and rollback transactions can be recovered automatically; Support use XA and non-XA connection pool together.  Unsupported Items  Recover committing and rolling back in other machines after the service is down.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seata BASE transaction</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-beta/en/features/transaction/use-norms/base-transaction-seata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-beta/en/features/transaction/use-norms/base-transaction-seata/</guid>
      <description>Supported Items  Support cross-database transactions after sharding; Support RC isolation level; Rollback transaction according to undo log; Support recovery committing transaction automatically after the service is down.  Unsupported Items  Do not support other isolation level except RC.  To Be Optimized Items  SQL will be parsed twice by Apache ShardingSphere and Seata.  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>