<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Article Selections on ShardingSphere - Blog</title>
    <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Article Selections on ShardingSphere - Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Revealing Sharding-Proxy —— Database Middleware Oriented DBA</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/proxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/proxy/</guid>
      <description>Revealing Sharding-Proxy —— Database Middleware Oriented DBA Lecturer introduction Yonglun Zhang: Senior software engineer of operation and maintenance department at JD Finance
He has been working on software development for years engaged in traditional Industry. Afterwards he was involved in Internet and started his web crawler career at JD Finance, sigh at the huge amount of Internet data since then. It&amp;rsquo;s great honor to join ShardingSphere this year and be able to do what he is interested in, he hopes to improve himself and contribute to the community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The quick explanation of ShardingSphere transaction module</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/realization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/realization/</guid>
      <description>Distributed Transaction Implementation on Sharding-Sphere Lecturer Jun Zhao
Work at JD Finance
Senior Java Development Engineer
 Years of internet development experience, love open source technology, full of interested in distributed storage. And familiar with online and realtime data processing with ElasticSearch、HBase、Presto、Storm and et.   Be responsible for distributed transaction implementation in Sharding-Sphere team.  Using Scenarios of Distributed Transaction ACID Everything starts with ACID(atomicity, consistency, isolation, durability). ACID are features of database local transaction as following,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to merge the child resultsets</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/result/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/result/</guid>
      <description>How to merge the child resultsets This series of articles is a hands-on introduction and analysis of SS&amp;rsquo;s core modules, the cutting-edge technologies used, and valuable lessons learned by SS&amp;rsquo;s core development members. This series of articles will take you into the world of SS kernel, to gain new knowledge and inspire. We hope you will pay attention to us, exchange ideas and go forward together.
Lecturers Liang Zhang, former head of Dangdang&amp;rsquo;s architecture department.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How automatic executor of ShardingSphere works</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/engine/</guid>
      <description>How automatic executor of ShardingSphere works Today「Analysis of Sharding-Sphere Series Articles」is brings you an introduction to the Sharding-Sphere automated execution engine module in this article. Since the boss prefers serious technical articles, I try my best to use a serious and solemn narrative style to share with you the topic of &amp;ldquo;Sharding-Sphere Automated Execution Engine Module&amp;rdquo;.
I just finished writing and sorting out the code of this module, so before I forget, I would like to share this with you, hope this article will help you all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Would you like to become an Apache committer</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/committer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/committer/</guid>
      <description>Would you like to become an Apache committer What is the Apache Software Foundation？ The Apache Software Foundation (Apache Software Foundation) is the most influential non-profit open source software project organization today. It was formally established in 1999 and is mainly composed of groups of developers and users. Under the leadership of the Apache Software Foundation, more than 350 top open source projects have graduated, including Apache HTTP Server, the world&amp;rsquo;s most famous web server software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The mixed open-source distributed transaction solution</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/solution/</guid>
      <description>The mixed open-source distributed transaction solution Author Liang Zhang，Leader of Data R&amp;amp;D of JD.com, initiator &amp;amp; PPMC of Apache ShardingSphere.
Love open source, currently leading open source project ShardingSphere (formerly known as Sharding-JDBC) and Elastic-Job. Good at using Java as the popular distributed architecture and Kubernetes and Mesos as the popular cloud platform, admiring elegant codes, and having more research on how to write expressive codes.
At present, focus on improving ShardingSphere to be the industry&amp;rsquo;s first-class financial data solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seata_AT</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/seata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/seata/</guid>
      <description>Apache ShardingSphere merged Seata AT distributed transactions Background Seata is a distributed transaction framework that jointly created by Ali group and Ant Financial services group. The current version of seata includes AT and TCC transaction. The goal of AT transaction is to provide incremental transaction ACID semantics under the micro service architecture, which let the users use distributed transactions just like local transactions. The core concept is the same as ShardingSphere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache ShardingSphere is included in CNCF Landscape</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/cncf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/cncf/</guid>
      <description>Apache ShardingSphere is included in CNCF Landscape CNCF (Cloud Native Computing Foundation)，is a cloud native computing open source software foundation founded by Google. It is committed to the popularization and sustainable development of Cloud Native technology. Cloud native technology helps enterprises and organizations to build and run agile and scalable applications in modern dynamic environments (such as public clouds, private clouds, and hybrid clouds) through a series of software, specifications, and standards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploration and expansion of the community</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/community/</guid>
      <description>Exploration and expansion of the Apache ShardingSphere community Apache ShardingSphere community was invited to attend the Apache Event-join Apache open source community held by at Tsinghua University on November 9th. As an honored speaker, Liang Zhang, the PPMC, gave a talk named exploring and expanding the Apache ShardingSphere community. The main points of this topic are as follows.
01 Why open source? For individuals, you can gain a better career and find enjoyment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to construct the distributed database</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/database/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/database/</guid>
      <description>How we build a distributed database Author | Liang Zhang
Relational databases have dominated the database field for the past few decades, and the stability, security, and ease of use they bring have become the cornerstone for building modern systems. With the rapid development of the Internet, the database structured in a stand-alone system has been unable to meet the increasingly high concurrent requests and increasingly large data storage needs, therefore, distributed database are more widely adopted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations on graduation of Apache ShardingSphere as a Top-Level Project!</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/graduate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/graduate/</guid>
      <description>Congratulations on graduation of Apache ShardingSphere as a Top-Level Project! Apache Software Foundation (ASF), The most popular open-source software foundation, announced Apache ShardingSphere as a Top-Level Project (TLP) on Wakefield, MA, 16th April 2020.
ShardingSphere entered into the Apache incubator since 10th November 2018. With the help of mentors and the whole community, The Apache board approved its graduation proposal with 10 +1 votes successfully, which ends up its 17 months incubator and promotes it as TLP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News! The distributed scheduling project ElasticJob set sail again</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/elasticjob/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/elasticjob/</guid>
      <description>News! The distributed scheduling project ElasticJob set sail again ElasticJob is a distributed scheduling solution that provides distributed task sharding, elastic scaling, fully automated discovery. , multitasking based on time-driven, data-driven, resident and ad-hoc task types, task aggregation and dynamic resource provisioning, fault detection, auto-remediation, and failover.Main features are as follows:
 Task aggregation Dynamic resource scheduling Fault detection and automatic repairing Failover and retry Full-featured operation platform and management tools Friendly with cloud-native  ElasticJob can fully meet enterprise user&amp;rsquo;s requirements on scheduling and processing ability for task management and batch jobs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After years of stagnation, ElasticJob is back with the first Apache version 3.0.0-alpha</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/alpha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/alpha/</guid>
      <description>After years of stagnation, ElasticJob is back with the first Apache version 3.0.0-alpha Within a few months ElasticJob as the subproject of Apache ShardingSphere has fixed and merged 535 issues and pull requests. More importantly, the ElasticJob community released the first official version: 3.0.0-alpha after joined Apache Software Foundation.
Background ElasticJob (https://github.com/apache/shardingsphere-elasticjob) is a distributed scheduling solution for internet ecology and massive tasks. ElasticJob consisting of two separate subprojects, ElasticJob-Lite and ElasticJob-Cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Following 6 months of development Apache ShardingSphere 5.0.0-beta has been officially released!</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/ss_5.0.0beta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/ss_5.0.0beta/</guid>
      <description>As an Apache top-level project, ShardingSphere goes through community verification, voting and many other steps before it can be released. Such steps ensure the release is compliant with the Apache Release License specifications, and meeting the users’ expectations set for the 5.0.0-beta milestone. The current version’s architecture has been completed and the version is officially available.
Release Features: 1.	Highlight Features DistSQL – A New SQL Type for a Distributed Database Ecosystem SQL is a database query programming language for accessing, querying, updating, and managing relational database systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why should you get involved in an Open-Source community?</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/open_source_community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/open_source_community/</guid>
      <description>You wouldn&amp;rsquo;t imagine how close Open-Source projects are to you, as they have been integrated into every aspect of our lives - from the office to your home, from gyms to restaurants etc.
The saying goes something along the lines of &amp;ldquo;Open-Source projects belong to us, not me&amp;rdquo; , which explains why these projects are popular to the point that even renowned business giants are including Open-Source initiatives into their roadmap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to DistSQL</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/jul_26_an_introduction_to_distsql/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/jul_26_an_introduction_to_distsql/</guid>
      <description>We believe that if you’re reading this then you’re familiar with SQL (Structured Query Language), the data query and programming language. It’s also used as the standard language of relational database management systems for accessing data, querying, updating and managing relational database systems.
Similar to standard SQL, DistSQL, or Distributed SQL, is a built-in SQL language unique to ShardingSphere that provides incremental functional capabilities beyond standard SQL. Leveraging ShardingSphere&amp;rsquo;s powerful SQL parsing engine, DistSQL provides a syntax structure and syntax validation system like that of standard SQL - making DistSQL more flexible while maintaining regularity.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>