<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Article Selections on ShardingSphere - Blog</title>
    <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Article Selections on ShardingSphere - Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Revealing Sharding-Proxy —— Database Middleware Oriented DBA</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/proxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/proxy/</guid>
      <description>Lecturer introduction Yonglun Zhang: Senior software engineer of operation and maintenance department at JD Finance
He has been working on software development for years engaged in traditional Industry. Afterwards he was involved in Internet and started his web crawler career at JD Finance, sigh at the huge amount of Internet data since then. It&amp;rsquo;s great honor to join ShardingSphere this year and be able to do what he is interested in, he hopes to improve himself and contribute to the community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The quick explanation of ShardingSphere transaction module</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/realization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/realization/</guid>
      <description>Lecturer Jun Zhao
Work at JD Finance
Senior Java Development Engineer
 Years of internet development experience, love open source technology, full of interested in distributed storage. And familiar with online and realtime data processing with ElasticSearch、HBase、Presto、Storm and et.   Be responsible for distributed transaction implementation in Sharding-Sphere team.  Using Scenarios of Distributed Transaction ACID Everything starts with ACID(atomicity, consistency, isolation, durability). ACID are features of database local transaction as following,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to merge the child resultsets</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/result/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/result/</guid>
      <description>This series of articles is a hands-on introduction and analysis of SS&amp;rsquo;s core modules, the cutting-edge technologies used, and valuable lessons learned by SS&amp;rsquo;s core development members. This series of articles will take you into the world of SS kernel, to gain new knowledge and inspire. We hope you will pay attention to us, exchange ideas and go forward together.
Lecturers Liang Zhang, former head of Dangdang&amp;rsquo;s architecture department. A passion for open source, currently leading two open source projects Elastic-Job and Sharding-Sphere (Sharding-JDBC).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How automatic executor of ShardingSphere works</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/engine/</guid>
      <description>Today「Analysis of Sharding-Sphere Series Articles」is brings you an introduction to the Sharding-Sphere automated execution engine module in this article. Since the boss prefers serious technical articles, I try my best to use a serious and solemn narrative style to share with you the topic of &amp;ldquo;Sharding-Sphere Automated Execution Engine Module&amp;rdquo;.
I just finished writing and sorting out the code of this module, so before I forget, I would like to share this with you, hope this article will help you all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Would you like to become an Apache committer</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/committer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/committer/</guid>
      <description>What is the Apache Software Foundation？ The Apache Software Foundation (Apache Software Foundation) is the most influential non-profit open source software project organization today. It was formally established in 1999 and is mainly composed of groups of developers and users. Under the leadership of the Apache Software Foundation, more than 350 top open source projects have graduated, including Apache HTTP Server, the world&amp;rsquo;s most famous web server software. Adhering to the spirit of &amp;ldquo;openness, innovation and community&amp;rdquo;, many Apache projects have established a strong and successful ecosystem, and the community is full of vitality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The mixed open-source distributed transaction solution</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/solution/</guid>
      <description>Author Liang Zhang，Leader of Data R&amp;amp;D of JD.com, initiator &amp;amp; PPMC of Apache ShardingSphere.
Love open source, currently leading open source project ShardingSphere (formerly known as Sharding-JDBC) and Elastic-Job. Good at using Java as the popular distributed architecture and Kubernetes and Mesos as the popular cloud platform, admiring elegant codes, and having more research on how to write expressive codes.
At present, focus on improving ShardingSphere to be the industry&amp;rsquo;s first-class financial data solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache ShardingSphere merged Seata AT distributed transactions</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/seata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/seata/</guid>
      <description>Background Seata is a distributed transaction framework that jointly created by Ali group and Ant Financial services group. The current version of seata includes AT and TCC transaction. The goal of AT transaction is to provide incremental transaction ACID semantics under the micro service architecture, which let the users use distributed transactions just like local transactions. The core concept is the same as ShardingSphere.
GitHub: https://github.com/seata/seata
Seata AT model The Seata AT transaction model includes TM (Transaction manager), RM (Resource manager) and TC (Transaction coordinator).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache ShardingSphere is included in CNCF Landscape</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/cncf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/cncf/</guid>
      <description>CNCF (Cloud Native Computing Foundation)，is a cloud native computing open source software foundation founded by Google. It is committed to the popularization and sustainable development of Cloud Native technology. Cloud native technology helps enterprises and organizations to build and run agile and scalable applications in modern dynamic environments (such as public clouds, private clouds, and hybrid clouds) through a series of software, specifications, and standards. The representative cloud-native technologies including containers, micro-services, micro-service governance, and declarative APIs, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploration and expansion of the community</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/community/</guid>
      <description>Apache ShardingSphere community was invited to attend the Apache Event-join Apache open source community held by at Tsinghua University on November 9th. As an honored speaker, Liang Zhang, the PPMC, gave a talk named exploring and expanding the Apache ShardingSphere community. The main points of this topic are as follows.
01 Why open source? For individuals, you can gain a better career and find enjoyment.
A better career   More career opportunities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to construct the distributed database</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/database/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/database/</guid>
      <description>Author | Liang Zhang
Relational databases have dominated the database field for the past few decades, and the stability, security, and ease of use they bring have become the cornerstone for building modern systems. With the rapid development of the Internet, the database structured in a stand-alone system has been unable to meet the increasingly high concurrent requests and increasingly large data storage needs, therefore, distributed database are more widely adopted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations on graduation of Apache ShardingSphere as a Top-Level Project!</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/graduate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/graduate/</guid>
      <description>Apache Software Foundation (ASF), The most popular open-source software foundation, announced Apache ShardingSphere as a Top-Level Project (TLP) on Wakefield, MA, 16th April 2020.
ShardingSphere entered into the Apache incubator since 10th November 2018. With the help of mentors and the whole community, The Apache board approved its graduation proposal with 10 +1 votes successfully, which ends up its 17 months incubator and promotes it as TLP.
As the first project graduating from Incubator in 2020, this cheering news was published subsequently on Apache official blog with the support of Sally Khudairi, Vice President Marketing &amp;amp; Publicity of ASF.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News! The distributed scheduling project ElasticJob set sail again</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/elasticjob/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/elasticjob/</guid>
      <description>ElasticJob is a distributed scheduling solution that provides distributed task sharding, elastic scaling, fully automated discovery. , multitasking based on time-driven, data-driven, resident and ad-hoc task types, task aggregation and dynamic resource provisioning, fault detection, auto-remediation, and failover.Main features are as follows:
 Task aggregation Dynamic resource scheduling Fault detection and automatic repairing Failover and retry Full-featured operation platform and management tools Friendly with cloud-native  ElasticJob can fully meet enterprise user&amp;rsquo;s requirements on scheduling and processing ability for task management and batch jobs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After years of stagnation, ElasticJob is back with the first Apache version 3.0.0-alpha</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/alpha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/alpha/</guid>
      <description>Within a few months ElasticJob as the subproject of Apache ShardingSphere has fixed and merged 535 issues and pull requests. More importantly, the ElasticJob community released the first official version: 3.0.0-alpha after joined Apache Software Foundation.
Background ElasticJob (https://github.com/apache/shardingsphere-elasticjob) is a distributed scheduling solution for internet ecology and massive tasks. ElasticJob consisting of two separate subprojects, ElasticJob-Lite and ElasticJob-Cloud. It was born in 2015, at that time the industry had outstanding job scheduling library such as QuartZ, but lacked of exploration at distributed field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Following 6 months of development Apache ShardingSphere 5.0.0-beta has been officially released!</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/ss_5.0.0beta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/ss_5.0.0beta/</guid>
      <description>As an Apache top-level project, ShardingSphere goes through community verification, voting and many other steps before it can be released. Such steps ensure the release is compliant with the Apache Release License specifications, and meeting the users’ expectations set for the 5.0.0-beta milestone. The current version’s architecture has been completed and the version is officially available.
Release Features: 1. Highlight Features DistSQL – A New SQL Type for a Distributed Database Ecosystem SQL is a database query programming language for accessing, querying, updating, and managing relational database systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why should you get involved in an Open-Source community?</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/open_source_community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/open_source_community/</guid>
      <description>You wouldn&amp;rsquo;t imagine how close Open-Source projects are to you, as they have been integrated into every aspect of our lives - from the office to your home, from gyms to restaurants etc.
The saying goes something along the lines of &amp;ldquo;Open-Source projects belong to us, not me&amp;rdquo; , which explains why these projects are popular to the point that even renowned business giants are including Open-Source initiatives into their roadmap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to DistSQL</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/jul_26_an_introduction_to_distsql/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/jul_26_an_introduction_to_distsql/</guid>
      <description>We believe that if you’re reading this then you’re familiar with SQL (Structured Query Language), the data query and programming language. It’s also used as the standard language of relational database management systems for accessing data, querying, updating and managing relational database systems.
Similar to standard SQL, DistSQL, or Distributed SQL, is a built-in SQL language unique to ShardingSphere that provides incremental functional capabilities beyond standard SQL. Leveraging ShardingSphere&amp;rsquo;s powerful SQL parsing engine, DistSQL provides a syntax structure and syntax validation system like that of standard SQL - making DistSQL more flexible while maintaining regularity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ShardingSphere’s Metadata Loading Process</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/oct_12_1_shardingspheres_metadata_loading_process/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/oct_12_1_shardingspheres_metadata_loading_process/</guid>
      <description>1. Overview
Metadata is the data that constitutes the data. In database terms, any data that describes the database is metadata. Column names, database names, usernames, table names, etc. and data customization library tables that store information about database objects are metadata. ShardingSphere core functions such as data sharding, encryption and decryption are all based on the database metadata.
This shows that metadata is the core of the ShardingSphere system and is also the core data of every data storage related middleware or component.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Distributed Database Middleware Ecosystem Driven by Open Source</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/oct_12_2_a_distributed_database_middleware_ecosystem_driven_by_open_source/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/oct_12_2_a_distributed_database_middleware_ecosystem_driven_by_open_source/</guid>
      <description>On July 21, 2021, Pan Juan, the SphereEx Co-Founder and Apache ShardingSphere PMC, was invited to give a keynote session at the 2021 AWS Cloud Summit Shanghai, on “Apache ShardingSphere: Open-Source Distributed Database Middleware Ecosystem Building”.
She introduced the expansion of the Open-Source project, community building, and how ShardingSphere practices the “Apache Way”. This article is a summary of Pan Juan’ s ideas.
A New Ecosystem Layer Positioned Above the Database &amp;amp; Under Business Applications Different industries, different users, different positionings, different requirements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Can Students Participate in Open-Source Communities?</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/oct_12_3_how_can_students_participate_in_open_source_communities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/oct_12_3_how_can_students_participate_in_open_source_communities/</guid>
      <description>Having some experience in Open-Source projects or communities is quite common for developers nowadays. Actually, not only adults but students should, and are increasingly likely to get involved in Open-Source projects.
If you want to know more about why you should consider being part of Open-Source projects, please refer to Why you should get involved in open-source community [1].
The last 2 years have been challenging to say the least. The Covid-19 pandemic has forever changed us in more ways than one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates and FAQ — Your 1 Minute Quick Start Guide to ShardingSphere</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/oct_12_4_updates_and_faq_your_1_minute_quick_start_guide_to_shardingsphere/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/oct_12_4_updates_and_faq_your_1_minute_quick_start_guide_to_shardingsphere/</guid>
      <description>Background Apache ShardingSphere is an Apache Top-Level project and is one of the most popular open-source big data projects. It was started about 5 years ago, and now ShardingSphere has over 14K+ stars and 270+ contributors in its community.
The successful project has already launched and updated many versions. Apache ShardingSphere now supports many powerful features and keeps optimizing its configuration rules. We want to help users understand all features and configuration rules, to help them quickly test and run components，and ultimately help them achieve best performance, so we decide to start the shardingsphere-example project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>E-Hualu X ShardingSphere | Hulu Story’s Data Processing Shortcut</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/oct_12_5_e_hualu_shardingsphere_hulu_story_data_processing_shortcut/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/oct_12_5_e_hualu_shardingsphere_hulu_story_data_processing_shortcut/</guid>
      <description>“ShardingSphere has greatly simplified sharding development and maintenance, which has played a very important role in our rapid product release. We estimate that ShardingSphere has saved us at least 4 months of R&amp;amp;D costs.” — Shi Moxuan, Technical Director，E-Hualu
 At the beginning of this year, E-hualu officially launched its cloud service product “Hulu App” that targets non-business users. Since then, its architecture’s data stress has increased on a daily basis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AutoTable: Your Butler-Like Sharding Configuration Tool</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/oct_12_6_autotable_your_butler_like_sharding_configuration_tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/oct_12_6_autotable_your_butler_like_sharding_configuration_tool/</guid>
      <description>Summary In the previous article “An Introduction to DistSQL” written by Haoran Meng, the Apache ShardingSphere Committer shared the motivating reasons behind the design of DistSQL, explained its syntax system, and impressively showcased how you can use one SQL to create a sharding table.
We believe that you should be now more familair with the new capabilities Apache ShardingSphere can bring you.
Following the article’s publication, we received many messages from our readers and users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>openGauss X ShardingSphere: One of the Top Distribution Solutions</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/oct_12_7_opengauss_shardingsphere_one_of_the_top_distribution_solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/oct_12_7_opengauss_shardingsphere_one_of_the_top_distribution_solutions/</guid>
      <description>About openGauss openGauss is an open source relational database management system. Since its launch in June 2020, it has made waves the database management vertical. With an increasing number of partners and developers, it’s already reaping the benefits of the significant efforts &amp;amp; resources poured into building a successful database ecosystem.
Project Background Facing problems like data volume explosion, and super-high levels of concurrent data processing, openGauss made a choice: to adopt a distributed solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ShardingSphere x Google Summer of Code: Students, How Was Your Open Source Experience?</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/oct_12_8_shardingsphere_google_summer_of_code_students_how_was_your_open_source_experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/oct_12_8_shardingsphere_google_summer_of_code_students_how_was_your_open_source_experience/</guid>
      <description>Recently the ShardingSphere community had the pleasure of contributing to the Google Summer of Code (GSoC), and mentoring the next generation of open source innovators. Our project was select to be part of this brilliant and long running program, to provide students from all over the world with an experience in open source software.
Thanoshan and Liangda are the students that worked with Apache ShardingSphere mentors during the latest GSoC, and continue contributing to the project ever since.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ShardingSphere x JD Baitiao: Story of an Implementation Journey</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/oct_12_9_shardingsphere_jd-baitiao_story_of_an_implementation_journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/oct_12_9_shardingsphere_jd-baitiao_story_of_an_implementation_journey/</guid>
      <description>Apache ShardingSphere has become the best solution for JD Baitiao&amp;rsquo;s very large storage scenarios and scale-up. JD&amp;rsquo;s shopping festival weighed very much on our big data storage. I mean, like hundreds of millions of data sets.
  JD Baitiao, an internet credit products provider launched in 2014, has always been challenged by data explosion. Every shopping festival is like a technical test for us, but every time the technical staff professionals take proactive strategic initiatives in data architecture development to ensure everything goes smoothly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache ShardingSphere 5.0.0 New Features: Middleware to Ecosystem Evolution</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/nov_22_5.0.0_new/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/nov_22_5.0.0_new/</guid>
      <description>Apache ShardingSphere 5.0.0 New Features: Middleware to Ecosystem Evolution Having undergone nearly two years of development and polishing with versions 5.0.0-Alpha and 5.0.0-Beta, Apache ShardingSphere 5.0.0 GA version will finally be available in November.
Coincidentally November 10th marks the 3rd anniversary of ShardingSphere’s entry into the Apache Software Foundation. The ShardingSphere core team has been working hard together with the community to meet this special deadline and release the 5.0.0 GA version to celebrate the third anniversary with the broader community, and entire distributed database and security ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating SCTL into RAL</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/nov_23_1_integrate_sctl_into_ral/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/nov_23_1_integrate_sctl_into_ral/</guid>
      <description>Integrating SCTL into RAL In the previous article “An Introduction to DistSQL” written by Haoran Meng, the Apache ShardingSphere Committer shared the motivating reasons behind the design of DistSQL, explained its syntax system, and impressively showcased how you can use one SQL to create a sharding table.
Recently, the ShardingSphere community has redesigned the SCTL grammar and the execution engine, integrating SCTL into the DistSQL syntax system. Now RAL contains the old SCTL function, making ShardingSphere&amp;rsquo;s command language even more convenient for database management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a Distributed Database Solution Based on PostgreSQL/openGauss</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/jan_28_blog_pg_create_a_distributed_database_solution_based_on_postgresql__opengauss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/jan_28_blog_pg_create_a_distributed_database_solution_based_on_postgresql__opengauss/</guid>
      <description>Create a Distributed Database Solution Based on PostgreSQL/openGauss As the MySQL ShardingSphere-Proxy is becoming mature and widely accepted, ShardingSphere is also focusing on the PostgreSQL ShardingSphere-Proxy.
Compared with the alpha and beta, lots of improvements such as PostgreSQL agreement realization, SQL support and control, have been made in ShardingSphere-Proxy 5.0.0. This lays the foundation for full docking with the PostgreSQL ecosystem in the future. The ecosystem integration of ShardingSphere-Proxy and PostgreSQL provides users, on the basis of PostgreSQL database, with transparent and enhanced capabilities, such as: data sharding, read/write splitting, shadow database, data masking and data desensitization as well as distributed governance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kernel Optimizations &amp; Upgrade Guide for Apache ShardingSphere 5.0.0 — The Ideal Database Management Ecosystem</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/jan_28_blog_x_kernel_optimizations__upgrade_guide_for_apache_shardingsphere_5.0.0_the_ideal_database_management_ecosystem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/jan_28_blog_x_kernel_optimizations__upgrade_guide_for_apache_shardingsphere_5.0.0_the_ideal_database_management_ecosystem/</guid>
      <description>Kernel Optimizations &amp;amp; Upgrade Guide for Apache ShardingSphere 5.0.0 — The Ideal Database Management Ecosystem Having undergone almost two years of development and optimization, the Apache ShardingSphere 5.0.0 GA version has been recently released. Compared with the 4.1.1 GA version, the new version’s kernel is greatly improved:
  Kernel optimizations are subject to the pluggable architecture allowing users to combine kernel features as they wish.
  Aiming to improve SQL distributed query capabilities, the Federation Execution Engine is created to satisfy users’ needs in complex business scenarios.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Develop Your Distributed SQL Statement in Apache ShardingSphere</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/jan_28_blog_x_how_to-develop_your_distributed_sql_statement_in_apache_shardingsphere/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/jan_28_blog_x_how_to-develop_your_distributed_sql_statement_in_apache_shardingsphere/</guid>
      <description>How to Develop Your Distributed SQL Statement in Apache ShardingSphere In the previous articles &amp;ldquo;An Introduction to DistSQL&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Integrating SCTL Into DistSQL’s RAL— Making Apache ShardingSphere Perfect for Database Management&amp;rdquo;, the Apache ShardingSphere Committers shared the motivations behind the development of DistSQL, explained its syntax system, and impressively showcased how you can use just one SQL to create a sharding table.
Today, to help you gain a better understanding of DistSQL and develop your own DistSQL syntax, our community author analyzes the design &amp;amp; development process of DistSQL and showcases how you can implement a brand new DistSQL grammar in four stages of the development life cycle (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>F6 Automobile Technology’s Multimillion Rows of Data Sharding Strategy Based on Apache ShardingSphere</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/jan_28_f6_automobile_technologys_multimillion_rows_of_data_sharding_strategy_based_on_apache_shardings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/jan_28_f6_automobile_technologys_multimillion_rows_of_data_sharding_strategy_based_on_apache_shardings/</guid>
      <description>F6 Automobile Technology’s Multimillion Rows of Data Sharding Strategy Based on Apache ShardingSphere F6 Automobile Technology is an Internet platform company focusing on the informatization of the automotive aftermarket.
It helps automotive repair companies (clients) build their smart management systems to digitally transform the auto aftermarket. The data of different auto repair companies will certainly be isolated from each other, so theoretically the data can be stored in different tables of different databases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Detailed Guide to Apache ShardingSphere’s Operating Modes</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/jan_28_your_detailed_guide_to_apache_shardingspheres_operating_modes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/jan_28_your_detailed_guide_to_apache_shardingspheres_operating_modes/</guid>
      <description>Your Detailed Guide to Apache ShardingSphere’s Operating Modes In Apache ShardingSphere 5.0.0 GA version, we added the new concept Operating Mode and provided three configuration methods: Memory, Standalone, and Cluster. Why does ShardingSphere provide these operating modes? What are the differences between them in actual development scenarios?
This article is a guide for you to better understand ShardingSphere’s new operating modes.
Background: Distributed Governance Distributed governance is the foundation of cluster deployment in ShardingSphere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache ShardingSphere Enterprise Applications</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/jan_28_blog_apache_shardingsphere_enterprise_applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/jan_28_blog_apache_shardingsphere_enterprise_applications/</guid>
      <description>Apache ShardingSphere Enterprise Applications  To further understand application scenarios, enterprises’ needs, and improve dev teams’ understanding of Apache ShardingSphere, our community launched the “Enterprise Visits” series.
 Keep For our community’s first visit, we went to Asia’s leading workout &amp;amp; fitness trainer app maker “Keep” headquarters at Vanke Times Center, and shared our technologies with developers at Keep Co.
Way back in 2018, Keep had already deployed ShardingSphere capabilities such as sharding and read/write splitting in multiple application scenarios for its diversified lines of business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full Link Online Stress Testing for Production Database: Apache ShardingSphere Shadow Database Feature Upgrade</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/jan_28_full_link_online_stress_testing_for_production_database_apache_shardingsphere_shadow_database_feature_upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/jan_28_full_link_online_stress_testing_for_production_database_apache_shardingsphere_shadow_database_feature_upgrade/</guid>
      <description>Full Link Online Stress Testing for Production Database: Apache ShardingSphere Shadow Database Feature Upgrade What is full link stress testing? As the Internet industry is growing rapidly, businesses that operate with large amounts of data are seeing a rapid expansion.
Predictably, ever changing customer demand is having a significant impact on the stability of their whole systems. For example, online food delivery platforms receive most of their customer orders at noon and in the evening.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>