<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Article Selections on ShardingSphere</title>
    <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Article Selections on ShardingSphere</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploration and expansion of the community</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/community/</guid>
      <description>Exploration and expansion of the Apache ShardingSphere community The Apache ShardingSphere community was invited to participate in the event of &amp;ldquo;Apache Event——Entering the Apache Open Source Software Community&amp;rdquo; held at Tsinghua University on November 9. In the event, PPMC Zhang Liang of the Apache ShardingSphere community shared the topic of &amp;ldquo;Exploration and Expansion of the Apache ShardingSphere Community&amp;rdquo;. Main content is as follows.
01 Why open source? You can benefit from a better career and find enjoyment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graduate from Incubator</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/graduate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/graduate/</guid>
      <description>Congratulations on graduation of Apache ShardingSphere as a Top-Level Project! Wakefield, MA, April 16, 2020 &amp;ndash; The world&amp;rsquo;s largest open source software foundation, the Apache Software Foundation (ASF), announced Apache ShardingSphere as a Top-Level Project (TLP).
ShardingSphere was submitted to the Apache Incubator and entered incubation in November 2018. Afterwards, under the guidance of the mentor, the members of the Incubator Project Management Committee (IPMC) effectively manages the process of incubation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>