<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Article Selections on ShardingSphere - Blog</title>
    <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Article Selections on ShardingSphere - Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>After years of stagnation, ElasticJob is back with the first Apache version 3.0.0-alpha</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/alpha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/alpha/</guid>
      <description>TODO </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News! The distributed scheduling project ElasticJob set sail again</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/elasticjob/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/elasticjob/</guid>
      <description>News! The distributed scheduling project ElasticJob set sail again ElasticJob is a distributed scheduling solution that provieds distributed task sharding, elastic scaling, fully automated discovery. , multitasking based on time-driven, data-driven, resident and ad-hoc task types, task aggregation and dynamic resource provisioning, fault detection, auto-remediation, and failover.Main features are as follows:
 Task aggregation Dynamic resource scheduling Fault detection and automatic repairing Failover and retry Full-featured operation platform and management tools Friendly with cloud-native  ElasticJob can fully meet enterprise user&amp;rsquo;s requirements on scheduling and processing ability for task management and batch jobs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations on graduation of Apache ShardingSphere as a Top-Level Project!</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/graduate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/graduate/</guid>
      <description>Congratulations on graduation of Apache ShardingSphere as a Top-Level Project! Apache Software Foundation (ASF), The most popular open-source software foundation, announced Apache ShardingSphere as a Top-Level Project (TLP) on Wakefield, MA, 16th April 2020.
ShardingSphere entered into the Apache incubator since 10th November 2018. With the help of mentors and the whole community, The Apache board approved its graduation proposal with 10 +1 votes successfully, which ends up its 17 months incubator and promotes it as TLP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to construct the distributed database</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/database/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/database/</guid>
      <description>How we build a distributed database Author | Liang Zhang
Relational databases have dominated the database field for the past few decades, and the stability, security, and ease of use they bring have become the cornerstone for building modern systems. With the rapid development of the Internet, the database structured in a stand-alone system has been unable to meet the increasingly high concurrent requests and increasingly large data storage needs, therefore, distributed database are more widely adopted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploration and expansion of the community</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/community/</guid>
      <description>Exploration and expansion of the Apache ShardingSphere community Apache ShardingSphere community was invited to attend the Apache Event-join Apache open source community held by at Tsinghua University on November 9th. As an honored speaker, Liang Zhang, the PPMC, gave a talk named exploring and expanding the Apache ShardingSphere community. The main points of this topic are as follows.
01 Why open source? For individuals, you can gain a better career and find enjoyment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache ShardingSphere is included in CNCF Landscape</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/cncf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/cncf/</guid>
      <description>Apache ShardingSphere is included in CNCF Landscape CNCF (Cloud Native Computing Foundation)，is a cloud native computing open source software foundation founded by Google. It is committed to the popularization and sustainable development of Cloud Native technology. Cloud native technology helps enterprises and organizations to build and run agile and scalable applications in modern dynamic environments (such as public clouds, private clouds, and hybrid clouds) through a series of software, specifications, and standards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seata_AT</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/seata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/seata/</guid>
      <description>TODO </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The mixed open-source distributed transaction solution</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/solution/</guid>
      <description>The mixed open-source distributed transaction solution Author Liang Zhang，Leader of Data R&amp;amp;D of JD.com, initiator &amp;amp; PPMC of Apache ShardingSphere.
Love open source, currently leading open source project ShardingSphere (formerly known as Sharding-JDBC) and Elastic-Job. Good at using Java as the popular distributed architecture and Kubernetes and Mesos as the popular cloud platform, admiring elegant codes, and having more research on how to write expressive codes.
At present, focus on improving ShardingSphere to be the industry&amp;rsquo;s first-class financial data solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Would you like to become an Apache committer</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/committer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/committer/</guid>
      <description>Would you like to become an Apache committer What is the Apache Software Foundation？ The Apache Software Foundation (Apache Software Foundation) is the most influential non-profit open source software project organization today. It was formally established in 1999 and is mainly composed of groups of developers and users. Under the leadership of the Apache Software Foundation, more than 350 top open source projects have graduated, including Apache HTTP Server, the world&amp;rsquo;s most famous web server software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How automatic executor of ShardingSphere works</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/engine/</guid>
      <description>TODO </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to merge the child resultsets</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/result/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/result/</guid>
      <description>How to merge the child resultsets This series of articles is a hands-on introduction and analysis of SS&amp;rsquo;s core modules, the cutting-edge technologies used, and valuable lessons learned by SS&amp;rsquo;s core development members. This series of articles will take you into the world of SS kernel, to gain new knowledge and inspire. We hope you will pay attention to us, exchange ideas and go forward together.
Lecturers Liang Zhang, former head of Dangdang&amp;rsquo;s architecture department.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The quick explanation of ShardingSphere transaction module</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/realization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/realization/</guid>
      <description>TODO </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revealing Sharding-Proxy —— Database Middleware Oriented DBA</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/proxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/proxy/</guid>
      <description>Revealing Sharding-Proxy —— Database Middleware Oriented DBA Lecturer introduction Yonglun Zhang: Senior software engineer of operation and maintenance department at JD Finance
He has been working on software development for years engaged in traditional Industry. Afterwards he was involved in Internet and started his web crawler career at JD Finance, sigh at the huge amount of Internet data since then. It&amp;rsquo;s great honor to join ShardingSphere this year and be able to do what he is interested in, he hopes to improve himself and contribute to the community.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>