<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Article Selections on ShardingSphere</title>
    <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Article Selections on ShardingSphere</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>1.Congratulations on graduation of Apache ShardingSphere as a Top-Level Project!</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/graduate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/graduate/</guid>
      <description>Congratulations on graduation of Apache ShardingSphere as a Top-Level Project! Apache Software Foundation (ASF), The most popular open-source software foundation, announced Apache ShardingSphere as a Top-Level Project (TLP) on Wakefield, MA, 16th April 2020.
ShardingSphere entered into the Apache incubator since 10th November 2018. With the help of mentors and the whole community, The Apache board approved its graduation proposal with 10 +1 votes successfully, which ends up its 17 months incubator and promotes it as TLP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2.Exploration and expansion of the community</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/community/</guid>
      <description>Exploration and expansion of the Apache ShardingSphere community Apache ShardingSphere community was invited to attend the Apache Event-join Apache open source community held by at Tsinghua University on November 9th. As an honored speaker, Liang Zhang, the PPMC, gave a talk named exploring and expanding the Apache ShardingSphere community. The main points of this topic are as follows.
01 Why open source? For individuals, you can gain a better career and find enjoyment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3.Would you like to become an Apache committer</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/committer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/committer/</guid>
      <description>TODO </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4.Apache ShardingSphere is included in CNCF Landscape</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/cncf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/cncf/</guid>
      <description>Apache ShardingSphere is included in CNCF Landscape CNCF (Cloud Native Computing Foundation)，is a cloud native computing open source software foundation founded by Google. It is committed to the popularization and sustainable development of Cloud Native technology. Cloud native technology helps enterprises and organizations to build and run agile and scalable applications in modern dynamic environments (such as public clouds, private clouds, and hybrid clouds) through a series of software, specifications, and standards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5.How to construct the distributed database</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/database/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/database/</guid>
      <description>How we build a distributed database Author | Liang Zhang
In the past few decades, relational database continuously occupy an absolute dominant position in the field of databases. The advantages of relational database, like stability, safety, ease of use that are the cornerstone of a modern system. With the rapid development of the Internet, databases built on stand-alone systems are no longer able to meet higher and higher concurrent requests and larger and larger data storage requirements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6.News! The distributed scheduling project ElasticJob set sail again</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/elasticjob/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/elasticjob/</guid>
      <description>News! The distributed scheduling project ElasticJob set sail again ElasticJob is a distributed scheduling solution, providing distributed task sharding, resilience scale up and down, auto discovery. And also supports multiple type of task such as time-driven, data-driven, long-term and temporary task. Main features are as follows:
 Task aggregation Dynamic resource scheduling Fault detection and automatic repairing Failover and retry Full-featured operation platform and management tools Friendly with cloud-native  ElasticJob can fully meet enterprise user&amp;rsquo;s requirements on scheduling and processing ability for task management and batch jobs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7.proxy</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/proxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/proxy/</guid>
      <description>TODO </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8.The mixed open-source distributed transaction solution</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/solution/</guid>
      <description>The mixed open-source distributed transaction solution Author Liang Zhang，Head of Data R&amp;amp;D of JD.com, initiator of Apache ShardingSphere &amp;amp; PPMC
Love open source, currently leading open source projects ShardingSphere (formerly known as Sharding-JDBC) and Elastic-Job. Good at using Java as the main distributed architecture and Kubernetes and Mesos as the main cloud platform, admiring elegant code, and having more research on how to write expressive code.
At present, the main energy is invested in building ShardingSphere into the industry&amp;rsquo;s first-class financial data solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9.The quick explanation of ShardingSphere transaction module</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/realization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/realization/</guid>
      <description>TODO </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10.Seata_AT</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/seata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/seata/</guid>
      <description>TODO </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11.How automatic executor of ShardingSphere works</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/engine/</guid>
      <description>TODO </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12.How to merge the child resultsets</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/result/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/material/result/</guid>
      <description>TODO </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>