<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Video Selections on ShardingSphere - Blog</title>
    <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/videos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Video Selections on ShardingSphere - Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/videos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cooperation Between ShardingSphere and openGauss</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/videos/opengauss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/videos/opengauss/</guid>
      <description>On May 29th, the &amp;ldquo;[Beijing] openGauss Meetup&amp;rdquo; event hosted by the openGauss community and jointly hosted by Beijing Kunpeng Joint Innovation Center, ENMOTECH, SANGFOR, and SphereEx was successfully held at Zhongguancun, Beijing. This Meetup is also the first joint event after SphereEx officially joined the openGauss community. At the Meetup site, Zhang Liang, CEO of SphereEx, shared the theme of &amp;ldquo;The Cooperation Between ShardingSphere and openGauss&amp;rdquo;.
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with Apache ShardingSphere</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/videos/opensource/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/videos/opensource/</guid>
      <description>Apache SharingSphere is the only database middleware project of Apache software foundation. It is mainly used in distributed database related scenarios such as data fragmentation, distributed transaction and distributed governance. This live broadcast will share why we want to participate in open source; the Apache software foundation, the core principles of Apache ShardingSphere and how to embark on the road of open source.
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to develop ShardingSphere community with Apache way</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/videos/build/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/videos/build/</guid>
      <description>Apache shardingsphere VP: Liang Zhang gives a wonderful explanation of shardingsphere project and open source. Liang Zhang, architecture expert of Technical Center, JD Digital Technology(JD.com), Apache ShardingSphere PMC Chair. Shardingsphere has entered the Apache incubator. It is the first open source project of JD to enter the Apache software foundation, and it is also the first distributed database of Apache software foundation.
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Apache ShardingSphere with the perspective of new SQL</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/videos/new_sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/videos/new_sql/</guid>
      <description>NewSQL is popular in recent years, and companies all over the world have different interpretations of NewSQL. This sharing will bring you the interpretation of NewSQL concept and product architecture around the world. The architecture, characteristics, planning and open source community of Apache ShardingSphere, a popular open source distributed database middleware service platform, are analyzed in detail from the perspective of NewSQL.
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache ShardingSphere architecture evolution driven by open source</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/videos/evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/videos/evolution/</guid>
      <description>This sharing will start with NewSQL, focusing on the evolution and planning of ShardingSphere architecture, and fall into the relationship and development between open source and contributors. From the perspective of product ecology, open source power, personal growth and development, it brings us interpretation and sharing.
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to build database ecosystem with newSQL in a big-data environment</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/videos/ecosystem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/videos/ecosystem/</guid>
      <description>With the rapid development of the Internet, the scale of Internet data is also explosive growth. In this scenario, how to transform and upgrade the traditional database to meet the data needs of the new Internet? How to build an ecosystem of distributed database cluster with the help of NewSQL concept to meet the business needs of query performance, large amount of data storage, data security, elastic expansion, etc? This sharing will analyze these problems in detail and provide a relatively complete NewSQL solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New feature of Apache ShardingSphere 5.x</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/videos/newfeature/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/blog/en/videos/newfeature/</guid>
      <description>The first version of Apache ShardingSphere 5.x will be released soon. In version 5.x, Apache ShardingSphere has made significant innovations from architecture design to product scope. Apache ShardingSphere 5.x follow pluggable architecture design concept to build a flexible, embeddable and extensible project. Apache ShardingSphere 5. X no longer takes data sharding as kernel, but turns to building distributed database ecosystem. In the new version, core functions such as data sharding, distributed transaction and database governance are completely separated from the kernel and become a part of its pluggable component.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>