<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scaling on ShardingSphere</title>
    <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-beta/en/features/scaling/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Scaling on ShardingSphere</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-beta/en/features/scaling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Core Concept</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-beta/en/features/scaling/concept/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-beta/en/features/scaling/concept/</guid>
      <description>Scaling Job It refers one complete process of scaling data from old sharding rules to new sharding rule.
Data Node Same as the Data Node in sharding/SQL.
Inventory Data It refers all existing data stored in data nodes before the scaling job started.
Incremental Data It refers the new data generated by application during scaling job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Principle</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-beta/en/features/scaling/principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-beta/en/features/scaling/principle/</guid>
      <description>Principle Description Consider about these challenges of ShardingSphere-Scaling, the solution is: Use two database clusters temporarily, and switch after the scaling is completed.
Advantages:
 No effect for origin data during scaling. No risk for scaling failure. No limited by sharding strategies.  Disadvantages：
 Redundant servers during scaling. All data needs to be moved.  ShardingSphere-Scaling will analyze the sharding rules and extract information like datasource and data nodes. According the sharding rules, ShardingSphere-Scaling create a scaling job with 4 main phases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User Norms</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-beta/en/features/scaling/use-norms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0-beta/en/features/scaling/use-norms/</guid>
      <description>Supported Items  Migrate out data into databases which managed by Apache ShardingSphere; Scale out data between data nodes of Apache ShardingSphere.  Unsupported Items  Do not support to scale tables without primary key.  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>