<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Contribute Guide on ShardingSphere</title>
    <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/contribute/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Contribute Guide on ShardingSphere</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/contribute/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributor Guide</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/contribute/contributor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/contribute/contributor/</guid>
      <description>You can report a bug, submit a new function enhancement suggestion, or submit a pull request directly.
Submit an Issue  Before submitting an issue, please go through a comprehensive search to make sure the problem cannot be solved just by searching. Check the Issue List to make sure the problem is not repeated. Create a new issue and choose the type of issue. Define the issue with a clear and descriptive title.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Set Up Your DEV Environment</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/contribute/dev-env/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/contribute/dev-env/</guid>
      <description>Git Installation Use the latest version.
You could download Git from Git Downloads.
If you&amp;rsquo;re running macOS or Linux, you could install Git from software repository.
Git Settings If you&amp;rsquo;re running Windows, following settings should be done before cloning ShardingSphere code.
Execute following command in PowerShell or cmd to prevent from filename too long error on cloning ShardingSphere code:
git config --global core.longpaths true JDK Installation Use JDK8+.
You could download JDK from OpenJDK Downloads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Documents Contribute Guide</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/contribute/document/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/community/en/involved/contribute/document/</guid>
      <description>If you want to help contribute shardingsphere documents or websites, we are happy to help you! Anyone can contribute, whether you&amp;rsquo;re new to a project or have been using shardingsphere for a long time, whether you&amp;rsquo;re a self identified developer, end-user, or someone who can&amp;rsquo;t stand typos,can contribute to documents or websites. In the contributor guide, we have mentioned how to submit Issues and pull request. here we will introduce how to submit pull request to document.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>