<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Core Concept on ShardingSphere</title>
    <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/3.0.0.M3/en/features/transaction/concept/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Core Concept on ShardingSphere</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/3.0.0.M3/en/features/transaction/concept/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>XA</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/3.0.0.M3/en/features/transaction/concept/xa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/3.0.0.M3/en/features/transaction/concept/xa/</guid>
      <description>2PC transaction submit uses the DTP Model defined by X/OPEN, in which created AP (Application Program), TM (Transaction Manager) and RM (Resource Manager) can guarantee a high transaction consistency. TM and RM use XA protocol for bidirectional streaming. Compared with traditional local transactions, XA transactions have a prepared phase, where the database cannot only passively receive commands, but also notify the submitter whether the transaction can be accepted. TM can collect all the prepared results of branch transactions before submitting all of them together, which has guaranteed the distributed consistency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BASE</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/3.0.0.M3/en/features/transaction/concept/base/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/3.0.0.M3/en/features/transaction/concept/base/</guid>
      <description>A paper published in 2008 first mentioned on BASE transaction, it advocates the use of eventual consistency to instead of consistency when improve concurrency of transaction processing.
TCC and Saga are two regular implementations. They use reverse operation implemented by developers themselves to ensure the eventual consistency when data rollback. SEATA implements SQL reverse operation automatically, so that BASE transaction can be used without the intervention of developers.
Apache ShardingSphere integrates SEATA as solution of BASE transaction.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>