<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shadow DB on ShardingSphere</title>
    <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0/en/features/shadow/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Shadow DB on ShardingSphere</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0/en/features/shadow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Core Concept</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0/en/features/shadow/concept/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0/en/features/shadow/concept/</guid>
      <description>Shadow DB Switch Shadow DB switch.
Pressure testing is a requirement for a specific period of time, turned on when needed.
Production DB The database used for production data.
Shadow DB The Shadow database for Pressure testing data isolation.
Shadow Table Pressure testing data related tables.
The shadow table has the same table structure in the production DB and shadow DB.
Shadow Algorithm Provides 2 types of shadow algorithms.
Since the shadow algorithm is closely related to business, no default shadow algorithm provided.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Norms</title>
      <link>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0/en/features/shadow/use-norms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shardingsphere.apache.org/document/5.0.0/en/features/shadow/use-norms/</guid>
      <description>Shadow database Supported  The database is MySQL, Oracle, PostgreSQL, SQLServer;  Unsupported  NoSQL database;  Shadow algorithm Supported  The note shadow algorithm supports MDL and DDL statements; The column shadow algorithm basically supports commonly used MDL statements;  Unsupported  Column shadow algorithm does not support DDL statements； The column shadow algorithm does not support range value matching operations, for example: subQuery, BETWEEN, GROUP BY &amp;hellip; HAVING&amp;hellip;; Use shadow library function + sub-library sub-table function, some special SQL is not supported, please refer toSQL Usage Specification  Column shadow algorithm DML statement support list  INSERT statement  Judge the inserted column and inserted value of INSERT operation</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>